<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CRUCIAL</title>
    <link>https://www.crucialab.net/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://www.crucialab.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>CRUCIAL</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 17:12:38 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.crucialab.net/media/logo_hu4e2de4b1cff4b5121e5bc4616029ffd0_52187_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>CRUCIAL</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expressions of Interest Invited</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/expression-of-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 17:12:38 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/expression-of-interest/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CRUCIAL is seeking research teams to participate in prediction markets for climate-related risks. Researchers from physical and social sciences with diverse expertise relevant to predicting physical climate risks and forecasting future greenhouse gas emissions and concentrations should register their interest. The markets will not be “pay-to-play” but an innovative way of distributing funding for climate forecasting, based on accuracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your research team, group, or organisation, has relevant expertise and is interested in being part of a radical new approach to aggregating information about climate risks please register and provide your details. This expression of interest implies no commitment to take part but means you will be considered as a potential participant and receive updates on the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Information gathatered as part of this Expression of Interest will only be used by CRUCIAL for the purpose of inviting participants to future climate-risk prediction markets, and will not be shared or transferred without permission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;expression-of-interest-form&#34;&gt;Expression of Interest form&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;form id=&#34;CRUCIAL EoI&#34; action=&#34;https://formspree.io/f/xrgwkbyk&#34; method=&#34;post&#34;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;name&#34; id=&#34;full-name&#34; placeholder=&#34;Name&#34; style=&#34;width:700px&#34; required=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;email&#34; name=&#34;_replyto&#34; id=&#34;email-address&#34; placeholder=&#34;email&#34; style=&#34;width:700px&#34; required=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;organization&#34; id=&#34;organization&#34; placeholder=&#34;Organization&#34; style=&#34;width:700px&#34; required=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;country&#34; id=&#34;country&#34; placeholder=&#34;Country&#34; style=&#34;width:700px&#34; required=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;text&#34; name=&#34;otype&#34; id=&#34;otype&#34; placeholder=&#34;Sector: Academia, Private, Govt, Non-profit, Other&#34; style=&#34;width:700px&#34; required=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;textarea rows=&#34;5&#34; name=&#34;expertise&#34; id=&#34;exprtise&#34; placeholder=&#34;Description of expertise.&#34; style=&#34;width:700px&#34; required=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;&lt;br&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; name=&#34;_subject&#34; id=&#34;email-subject&#34; value=&#34;CRUCIAL EoI&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;input type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Submit&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Climate Forecasting&#39;s Lemon Problem</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/fixing-climate-forecastings-lemon-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/fixing-climate-forecastings-lemon-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change will bring warmer temperatures, higher sea levels, and changes in rainfall and windstorms, although some of these consequences are far more certain than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can mitigate climate change by reducing emissions of greenhouse gases, but we will have to adapt to a different climate. Deciding how much we should adapt is a trillion-dollar question: Preparing for a worst-case scenario that doesn’t materialize could be as costly as failing to invest enough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desire to ensure that infrastructure and supply-chains are resilient to climate change has created a demand for more detailed climate forecasts. Climate modelling has historically been done by government-funded agencies, with access to supercomputers, but these are now being joined by a proliferation of private companies, ready to satisfy the need for more granular predictions of climate extremes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Commercial weather forecasters have been a source of innovation&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new industry of “climate analytics” has emerged. The influx of new providers, many backed by venture capital, is welcome. The private sector has provided weather forecasts for many years. Commercial weather forecasters have been a source of innovation and often tailor products to users, such as power companies needing to predict electricity demand. But weather and climate forecasts are different: You can verify weather forecasts after a few days, and in a few months, you’ll know if a forecaster is competent. It can be years, however, or even decades, before the skill of a climate forecaster becomes apparent. When providers are paid upfront for twenty-year forecasts it makes more sense for them to invest in slick marketing than in making their predictions more accurate. George Akerlof won a Nobel Prize for explaining how markets fail when buyers can not evaluate quality. He used the example of low-quality used cars, or “lemons”. Climate forecasting has its own lemon problem, with some products providing precision that cannot be justified, for example. Only sellers of low quality products benefit in this type of market. Consumers and sellers of high quality products lose out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Regulation is more likely to create barriers to entry, and stifle innovation, than to improve forecasts.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are deciding where to invest in farmland, or planning a city’s flood defences, there are many climate analytics providers to choose from, but no easy way to distinguish reliable ones from charlatans.   One response has, inevitably, been calls for regulation. But climate analytics is a new and fast-developing field. Novel approaches, including machine learning and AI, are being tried in addition to continual improvements to established methods. No regulator has the expertise to decide which techniques will succeed. Regulation is more likely to create barriers to entry, and stifle innovation, than to improve forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An alternative to regulation would be to replace the existing and extemporary marketplace for climate analytics, which rewards marketing prowess, with a deliberately designed market which rewards accuracy. Futures markets settled on climate-related variables, rather than asset prices, would achieve this. The markets would not be for hedging risks but for aggregating the expertise of participants and providing incentives for them to get it right. Markets designed to obtain information, rather than transfer assets or risks, are dubbed “prediction markets”. Their prevailing prices can be interpreted as probabilities of different outcomes — implied forecasts emerging from the collective wisdom of participants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the absence of hedgers, a climate prediction market would need to be subsidized — we shouldn’t expect to get information for free. There is a case that climate predictions should be a public good so the government could provide some subsidies. Governments are already spending millions of dollars on climate forecasting research and a well-designed market could channel this funding to providers based on performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prediction markets have been suggested as a tool for policymakers in the past but have failed to catch on. Anti-gambling laws have been an obstacle but so has a lack of subsidies to attract participants to markets on specialized topics. Getting governments to rethink the way they fund climate forecasting is a major challenge, but companies and philanthropists can lead the way. They can pioneer a more efficient and transparent way of distributing money than selecting and contracting with individual providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies, public agencies, and non-profits who want more accurate climate forecasts, as well as providers investing in R&amp;amp;D to make them more accurate, have an interest in fixing the market for climate forecasts. The more accurately we can predict future climate, the more cost effectively we can adapt to it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original version of this article appeared as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.linkedin.com/pulse/fixing-climate-forecastings-lemon-problem-mark-roulston%3FtrackingId=%252BO7dddAxQQiuTcDGWtvfCA%253D%253D/?trackingId=%2BO7dddAxQQiuTcDGWtvfCA%3D%3D&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fixing Climate Forecasting&amp;rsquo;s Lemon Problem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expert Prediction Markets for Climate Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/event/pentland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/event/pentland/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A viability study of joint-outcome prediction markets for climate risk</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/event/dmu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/event/dmu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two projects on learning from markets: bank runs and climate change predictions</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/event/huji-eem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/event/huji-eem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;* The image is an allusion to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.hafakulta.agri.huji.ac.il/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Robert H. Smith Faculty of Agriculture, Food and Environment&lt;/a&gt;,
which is closely associated with the development of the cherry tomato.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginner&#39;s guide to trading on AGORA prediction markets</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AGORA is a platform for hosting prediction markets in which participants can bet 
on the outcome of events or the values of particular quantities. This article is 
an introduction to trading on AGORA prediction markets. We will cover the 
mechanics of how you place trades and also offer some tips on how to translate 
your judgments and opinions into trading strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have been invited to participate in an AGORA market then you can login to the platform and you will see a screen showing a list of the individual markets open to you (your list will be different to the one below).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-1-an-example-of-a-list-of-markets-available-to-one-participant-on-agora&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Markets menu&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/markets-menu_hu4d67628b1389b7eb631f1e436ebe9fd2_29104_cbef5a41921d8d33cb50ddc9ba6872e1.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/markets-menu_hu4d67628b1389b7eb631f1e436ebe9fd2_29104_af89659ab12e34cbdfbe0a2955e41d45.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/markets-menu_hu4d67628b1389b7eb631f1e436ebe9fd2_29104_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/markets-menu_hu4d67628b1389b7eb631f1e436ebe9fd2_29104_cbef5a41921d8d33cb50ddc9ba6872e1.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;548&#34;
               height=&#34;488&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 1&lt;/strong&gt;: An example of a list of markets available to one participant on AGORA.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you click on the “accounts” icon (the head and shoulders) you will see a list of your accounts with the markets that use that account listed underneath each one. If two markets belong to the same account then credits earned in one market may be used in the other market but credits cannot be transferred from a market under one account to a market under another account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-2-a-list-of-one-participants-accounts-in-agora-the-markets-associated-with-each-account-are-listed-under-the-account-name&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Accounts view&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/accounts_hu93d726f6db857f078380c1f5ed1f665b_35317_b4fc0e0924d1248a6951b3aa69f3966c.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/accounts_hu93d726f6db857f078380c1f5ed1f665b_35317_6bdc2f46986db020b9c54744d79c5113.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/accounts_hu93d726f6db857f078380c1f5ed1f665b_35317_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/accounts_hu93d726f6db857f078380c1f5ed1f665b_35317_b4fc0e0924d1248a6951b3aa69f3966c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;616&#34;
               height=&#34;546&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 2&lt;/strong&gt;: A list of one participant’s accounts in AGORA. The markets associated with each account are listed under the account name.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;defining-contracts-and-placing-trades&#34;&gt;Defining Contracts and Placing Trades&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To trade, you select the “markets” icon (the four panels) and then select a market, 
e.g. the “Strictly Come Dancing Winner” market. This demonstration market is for 
predicting the winner of the 2018 series of BBC’s &lt;em&gt;Strictly Come Dancing&lt;/em&gt; programme 
(Americans will know this programme as &lt;em&gt;Dancing with the Stars&lt;/em&gt;). In the programme 
15 celebrities compete at dancing with one celebrity being ejected from the competition 
each week. This market is, as the British election commentator Peter Snow might say, 
“just a bit of fun”, but it illustrates many of the key features of AGORA. This market 
has 15 distinct outcomes. In all AGORA markets, outcomes are &lt;em&gt;Mutually Exclusive and 
Comprehensively Exhaustive&lt;/em&gt; (MECE): this means that only one outcome can occur but 
one outcome must occur.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-3-the-market-for-the-winner-of-the-2018-series-of-the-bbcs-strictly-come-dancing-programme-this-snapshot-was-taken-in-the-second-week-of-the-competition&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;MECE&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/mece_hu5f3086f7766d7f185170d48ee1ac3e9f_48451_ee34bcb4091738ba034f6e046f775f6d.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/mece_hu5f3086f7766d7f185170d48ee1ac3e9f_48451_3a37eaf00395d8e39c224f7c8e1cee4d.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/mece_hu5f3086f7766d7f185170d48ee1ac3e9f_48451_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/mece_hu5f3086f7766d7f185170d48ee1ac3e9f_48451_ee34bcb4091738ba034f6e046f775f6d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;431&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 3&lt;/strong&gt;: The market for the winner of the 2018 series of the BBC’s Strictly Come Dancing Programme. (This snapshot was taken in the second week of the competition.)
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The figure above is the market screen for the &lt;em&gt;Strictly&lt;/em&gt; market. The number of credits you have in this market space is shown at the top. The current prices for each outcome are shown in the bar graph. The favourite is Joe Sugg with a price of 0.132. This price can be interpreted as the probability of Joe Sugg winning. AGORA allows you to define contracts that cover one or more outcomes. You can then buy one or more of the contracts you define. At settlement you will receive 1.00 credit for each contract you hold that covers the outcome that actually occurs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To define a contract click on the “+” icon, then click on one or more outcomes that you want covered by the contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-4-defining-a-contract-that-will-pay-out-100-credit-if-joe-sugg-wins&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Defining a contract&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/defining-a-contract_hu4f7759361ecbf132e7096f73d6e46c83_53597_070b2377c494247304b4570eccec09d3.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/defining-a-contract_hu4f7759361ecbf132e7096f73d6e46c83_53597_a2df783d3210d1252ae1a04e39361c06.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/defining-a-contract_hu4f7759361ecbf132e7096f73d6e46c83_53597_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/defining-a-contract_hu4f7759361ecbf132e7096f73d6e46c83_53597_070b2377c494247304b4570eccec09d3.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;629&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 4&lt;/strong&gt;: Defining a contract that will pay out 1.00 credit if Joe Sugg wins.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The simplest type of contract covers a single outcome. For example, the figure above shows a contract that covers Joe Sugg winning. AGORA has automatically named this contract “Joe Sugg” but you are free to rename the contract if you want. Contract definitions are specific to you — other participants do not see your contracts and must define their own. If you click “create” the Joe Sugg contract is created.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contracts can cover more than one outcome. For example, you can create a contract covering all the female contestants and name the contract “Female Winner”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-5-defining-a-contract-that-will-pay-out-100-credit-a-female-wins&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Composite contract; a female will win&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/composite-contract-female_hu13d24f84a7522dc233e66d1aed4c06e1_50414_30be7b9c7589bffe0963a35b04b96d1b.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/composite-contract-female_hu13d24f84a7522dc233e66d1aed4c06e1_50414_126abca04930b110011cc1e4ee85927d.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/composite-contract-female_hu13d24f84a7522dc233e66d1aed4c06e1_50414_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/composite-contract-female_hu13d24f84a7522dc233e66d1aed4c06e1_50414_30be7b9c7589bffe0963a35b04b96d1b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;645&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 5&lt;/strong&gt;: Defining a contract that will pay out 1.00 credit a female wins.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-6-portfolio-of-defined-contracts&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Portfolio of contracts&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/portfolio-of-contracts_hu9dce601e9fe363fc2979e90659393db7_51181_e8b77afbb354e193ede19e9d44f8c2c3.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/portfolio-of-contracts_hu9dce601e9fe363fc2979e90659393db7_51181_8256d1e46a927cefa77a2529c847c639.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/portfolio-of-contracts_hu9dce601e9fe363fc2979e90659393db7_51181_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/portfolio-of-contracts_hu9dce601e9fe363fc2979e90659393db7_51181_e8b77afbb354e193ede19e9d44f8c2c3.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;538&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 6&lt;/strong&gt;: Portfolio of defined contracts.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your portfolio is shown below the price bar chart. AGORA uses a market maker that will always quote a price for a contract. These prices are shown in the PRICE column. The QUANTITY column shows how many units of each contract you currently hold. To buy contracts you can either specify the number you wish to have in the QUANTITY field or you can specify a change in your inventory in the ORDER field. Although you have defined two contracts you have not yet bought any so you can delete the definitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-7-you-can-buy-contracts-by-either-specifying-the-quantity-you-want-to-have-in-your-inventory-or-specifying-an-order-change-in-inventory&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Buying contracts&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/buying-contracts_hu8f31a719b2b6c0dbe00428aa6581ad1e_52727_df33eb027c0949f20463c6c8f8383c2a.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/buying-contracts_hu8f31a719b2b6c0dbe00428aa6581ad1e_52727_f0599dce52aea779b81464fb35d57dc1.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/buying-contracts_hu8f31a719b2b6c0dbe00428aa6581ad1e_52727_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/buying-contracts_hu8f31a719b2b6c0dbe00428aa6581ad1e_52727_df33eb027c0949f20463c6c8f8383c2a.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;530&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 7&lt;/strong&gt;: You can buy contracts by either specifying the quantity you want to have in your inventory or specifying an order (change in inventory).
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the figure above, an order to buy 100 of the Joe Sugg contract has been placed and the market maker is quoting a price of 0.138 per contract. This is slightly higher than the 0.132 in the PRICE column because the market maker raises the price a bit in response to the buy order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-8-you-can-sell-contracts-by-placing-a-negative-order&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Selling contracts&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/selling-contracts_hu79cc4a70858e9b4109ea3f9b4ab8553e_53227_9d29f00fbbd6f303c466577e810c8a0a.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/selling-contracts_hu79cc4a70858e9b4109ea3f9b4ab8553e_53227_42e6cad35a96a66542a342ad6b063df4.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/selling-contracts_hu79cc4a70858e9b4109ea3f9b4ab8553e_53227_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/selling-contracts_hu79cc4a70858e9b4109ea3f9b4ab8553e_53227_9d29f00fbbd6f303c466577e810c8a0a.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;555&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 8&lt;/strong&gt;: You can sell contracts by placing a negative order.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;going-long-and-going-short&#34;&gt;Going Long and Going Short&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since a contract pays out 1.00 credit if an outcome covered by the contract occurs it follows that the expected value of the contract is the probability that the outcome occurs. If you think that the probability of a contract paying out is substantially higher than the quoted price then you have a reason to buy the contract, or “go long” in the parlance of financial markets. But, what if you think the quoted price of a contract is significantly higher than the probability of it paying out? In other words, what if you think a contract is overvalued? How can you exploit such a mispricing? The AGORA platform does not allow you to “go short” — sell contracts you don’t already own — which is what speculators do to stocks they think are overpriced. However, the prices of all outcomes always sum to 1.00: if you buy one unit of every outcome it will cost you 1.00 (but you are guaranteed a pay out of 1.00 at settlement). This means that if you think any outcome is overvalued there must be other outcomes that are undervalued.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;!(Selling the complementary contract; going short](complementary-contract.png &amp;ldquo;Figure 9**: If you think Ashley Roberts is overvalued we can define a complementary contract which will be undervalued.&amp;rdquo;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, suppose you think that former Pussycat Doll Ashley Roberts is overvalued — yes she’s good but you think the judges and voting public will be harsher on her due to her previous dancing experience — you can define a contract covering all the other contestants as shown above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-10-the-prices-of-the-contracts-not-ashley-roberts-and-ashley-roberts-sum-to-100-if-we-think-ashley-roberts-is-overvalued-it-follows-that-not-ashley-roberts-is-undervalued-and-we-should-buy-it&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Complementary contract example&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/complementary-contract-example_huca81a144d3ef6e05705904e49fa02669_60103_88f272abb58a168aa8d30fcdfd820831.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/complementary-contract-example_huca81a144d3ef6e05705904e49fa02669_60103_f76285850e5d9d9667d94c2af3471a29.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/complementary-contract-example_huca81a144d3ef6e05705904e49fa02669_60103_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/complementary-contract-example_huca81a144d3ef6e05705904e49fa02669_60103_88f272abb58a168aa8d30fcdfd820831.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;586&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 10&lt;/strong&gt;: The prices of the contracts NOT Ashley Roberts and Ashley Roberts sum to 1.00. If we think Ashley Roberts is overvalued it follows that NOT Ashley Roberts is undervalued and we should buy it.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate that contracts covering complete sets of outcomes sum to 1.00 you can also define a contract for Ashley Roberts. The prices of these two complementary contracts sum to 1.00. If you think the “Ashley Roberts” contract is overvalued the contract “NOT Ashley Roberts” must be undervalued, so you can express your view by buying this contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;markets-for-continuous-quantities&#34;&gt;Markets for Continuous Quantities&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Strictly Come Dancing&lt;/em&gt; market is an example of a market for a categorical variable that can take on one of several distinct values. AGORA also supports markets for continuous variables by partitioning the variable into discrete intervals. To illustrate this lets look at a demonstration market for the UK unemployment rate in the final quarter of 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-11-the-uk-unemployment-rate-can-be-partitioned-into-intervals-of-01-this-interval-covers-the-range-54-to-84&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Continuous outcome partitioning&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/continuous-outcome-partitioning_hu7aeacf7da383616186acbb227fd0915e_39830_21f4f7a0d39d9b577596fbf60876a51b.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/continuous-outcome-partitioning_hu7aeacf7da383616186acbb227fd0915e_39830_635ef96e649818c04ef2694d22489d89.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/continuous-outcome-partitioning_hu7aeacf7da383616186acbb227fd0915e_39830_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/continuous-outcome-partitioning_hu7aeacf7da383616186acbb227fd0915e_39830_21f4f7a0d39d9b577596fbf60876a51b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;630&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 11&lt;/strong&gt;: The UK Unemployment rate can be partitioned into intervals of 0.1%. This interval covers the range 5.4% to 8.4%.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Office of National Statistics reports the UK unemployment rate to an accuracy of 
0.1% so this is a sensible interval for partitioning this variable. Trading individual 
outcomes covering just 0.1% would be cumbersome but because of the way AGORA lets you 
define contracts you can create contracts covering intervals, including multiple 
disjoint intervals. Note that the individual intervals for unemployment are represented 
as intervals that are “closed” at the lower end and “open” on the upper end. This is 
written as [8.3%,8.4%) and means the interval includes 8.3% but not 8.4%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Bayesian statistics a credible interval is a range in which a variable will fall with a specified subjective probability. Let’s suppose &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; 90% credible interval for UK unemployment in Q4 of 2019 is 5.4% to 8.4%. You can define a contract covering this interval and get a price quote for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-12-the-price-of-the-interval-54-to-84-is-0222&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Price of credible interval&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/price-of-interval_hu7182bcff20c89bf5ebcf955e8e161054_38204_e477f20bc6e0ad9464dd5581455f3c94.webp 400w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/price-of-interval_hu7182bcff20c89bf5ebcf955e8e161054_38204_38b6f0432a9cc2593f6f871e51faebbc.webp 760w,
               /post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/price-of-interval_hu7182bcff20c89bf5ebcf955e8e161054_38204_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/beginners-guide-to-trading-on-agora-prediction-markets/price-of-interval_hu7182bcff20c89bf5ebcf955e8e161054_38204_e477f20bc6e0ad9464dd5581455f3c94.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;523&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 12&lt;/strong&gt;: The price of the interval 5.4% to 8.4% is 0.222.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the example above, you are being quoted a price of just 0.222 for this interval. 
If you really think the probability of the true value falling in this range is 90% 
this contract has an expected value of 0.90 so it’s a very good buy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-settlement&#34;&gt;Market Settlement&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a market settles, all contracts covering the correct outcome pay out 1.00 credit 
which is added to your credit balance. All other contracts are worthless. All AGORA 
markets are denominated in credits. 
In markets run by CRUCIAL, these credits represent shares of the segregated research funding pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this article will have introduced you to AGORA and enabled you to start trading 
in markets in which you have been invited to participate. As you become more familiar with 
AGORA markets you may wish to implement more intricate trading strategies using the API. 
Trading using the API will be the topic of a future article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an updated version of an article which appeared on Medium 11.10.2018 as &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/hvmd/a-beginners-guide-to-trading-prediction-markets-on-hivemind-agora-95e0df9c45d7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;A beginner’s guide to trading prediction markets on Hivemind AGORA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-disciplinary problem</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/multi-disciplinary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 21:00:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/multi-disciplinary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The top 4 emitters &amp;ndash; China, the USA, India, and Russia &amp;ndash; account for 55% of annual
CO2 emissions from fossil fuels. These country emissions are anthropogenic and exogenous
to physical-science based climate modelling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To develop an understanding of the anthropogenic contribution to future CO2 concentrations,
there is a need for &lt;em&gt;country specialists&lt;/em&gt; in the politics, energy policies, environmental
regulations, and economics of each substantial emitter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-co2-emissions-from-fossil-fuels-by-country-2019&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Country breakdown of fossil-fuel CO2 emissions&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/multi-disciplinary/multi-disciplinary_national_CO2_shares_hu1e271bf1e98a3ccc92d1863f5d3e86fa_292185_b743bbb64e4e42d977877ad8f82ed364.webp 400w,
               /challenge/multi-disciplinary/multi-disciplinary_national_CO2_shares_hu1e271bf1e98a3ccc92d1863f5d3e86fa_292185_b9adb656bb5f16906882ee6a6db8d940.webp 760w,
               /challenge/multi-disciplinary/multi-disciplinary_national_CO2_shares_hu1e271bf1e98a3ccc92d1863f5d3e86fa_292185_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/multi-disciplinary/multi-disciplinary_national_CO2_shares_hu1e271bf1e98a3ccc92d1863f5d3e86fa_292185_b743bbb64e4e42d977877ad8f82ed364.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;469&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: CO2 emissions from fossil fuels by country, 2019
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas each successive COP meeting generates easily accessible and centrally collated statements of
CO2-reduction intent, nations will differ in the extent to which these commitments are monitored
and enforced. Already at this time, there is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s43247-021-00097-8#Fig3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;great variability between countries in the probability
of achieving Paris Agreement Goals&lt;/a&gt;.
These dynamics fall squarely within the social and policy sciences, which currently
receive only a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2214629619309119&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;tiny fraction&lt;/a&gt;
of climate research funding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Abundance of Choice</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 17:28:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Complex statistical analysis and mathematical modelling involve multitudes of
choices and assumptions. Recent &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;many analysts, one data set&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; studies show the
danger of relying solely on one research team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here we present several examples from this literature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also present an example from climate modelling in which variations
in modelling choices account for a greater share of variance than variations in
scenario choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;h2 id=&#34;silberzahn-et-al-2018httpsjournalssagepubcomdoiabs1011772515245917747646-----social-science-psychology&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/2515245917747646&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Silberzahn et al. (2018)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; social science, psychology&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty-nine teams involving 61 analysts used the same data set to address the same
research question: whether soccer referees are more likely to give red cards to
dark-skin-toned players than to light-skin-toned players. &amp;hellip;Twenty teams (69%) found a
statistically significant positive effect, and 9 teams (31%) did not observe a significant
relationship. Overall, the 29 different analyses used 21 unique combinations of covariates.
&lt;em&gt;&amp;hellip;significant variation in the results of analyses of complex data may be difficult
to avoid, even by experts with honest intentions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-table-covariates-included-by-each-team&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Covariates included by each team&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_table_hucff2bad6104e6c8ad58ba87240b01630_143415_0bf380a3f7d7296e188a98256b7ff0e7.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_table_hucff2bad6104e6c8ad58ba87240b01630_143415_f6af3706076fddae0d7b0e6a2d51f33f.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_table_hucff2bad6104e6c8ad58ba87240b01630_143415_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_table_hucff2bad6104e6c8ad58ba87240b01630_143415_0bf380a3f7d7296e188a98256b7ff0e7.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;283&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Table: Covariates included by each team.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-odds-ratios-across-29-teams&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Odds Ratios across 29 teams&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_team_hub94d93adb1091de03a6f2571854b40c8_373684_3c2e96873026dd2b8ba9f03ba84a87ee.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_team_hub94d93adb1091de03a6f2571854b40c8_373684_43c18810f7705b2c7bf9612fe0a3a906.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_team_hub94d93adb1091de03a6f2571854b40c8_373684_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_team_hub94d93adb1091de03a6f2571854b40c8_373684_3c2e96873026dd2b8ba9f03ba84a87ee.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;408&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: Odds ratios across 29 teams.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-or-point-estimates-clustered-by-analytic-approach&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;OR point estimates clustered by analytic approach&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_analytic_approach_hue12b52ba6f142b35d3da4c25d1212a03_822901_cb89893110826cb53b03f39d7beef117.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_analytic_approach_hue12b52ba6f142b35d3da4c25d1212a03_822901_c20f5003f5948319eb4eecd99225a541.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_analytic_approach_hue12b52ba6f142b35d3da4c25d1212a03_822901_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/silber_ORs_by_analytic_approach_hue12b52ba6f142b35d3da4c25d1212a03_822901_cb89893110826cb53b03f39d7beef117.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;444&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: OR point estimates clustered by analytic approach.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The observed results from analyzing a complex data set
can be highly contingent on justifiable, but subjective,
analytic decisions. Uncertainty in interpreting research
results is therefore not just a function of statistical power
or the use of questionable research practices; it is also
a function of the many reasonable decisions that
researchers must make in order to conduct the research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huntington-klein-et-al-2021httpsonlinelibrarywileycomdoiepdf101111ecin12992-----economics&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/epdf/10.1111/ecin.12992&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Huntington-Klein et al. (2021)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; economics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These researchers ask whether two published empirical studies reporting causal
empirical results replicate when this is attempted by multiple research teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black et al. (2008) Staying in the classroom and out of the maternity ward?
The effect of compulsory schooling laws on teenage births. &lt;em&gt;The Economic Journal&lt;/em&gt;,
118(530): 1025&amp;ndash;1054. &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/ej/article-abstract/118/530/1025/5089485&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fairlie et al. (2011) Is employer-based health insurance a barrier to entrepreneurship?
&lt;em&gt;Journal of Health Economics&lt;/em&gt;, 30(1): 146&amp;ndash;162. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rand.org/pubs/working_papers/WR637-1.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They recruit 49 published researchers to participate in replication teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After attrition (due to a short completion window), they obtained 7 independent
replications of each study.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-results-from-compulsory-education-1-replication-study&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Compulsory education&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_compulsory_education_huf21826a9f73f65d5737f6ada49f4b8c0_53902_3bd7d97ba3139c197adbe686d8728a8e.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_compulsory_education_huf21826a9f73f65d5737f6ada49f4b8c0_53902_ed5f9216e153b118d9c09b6d681727d5.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_compulsory_education_huf21826a9f73f65d5737f6ada49f4b8c0_53902_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_compulsory_education_huf21826a9f73f65d5737f6ada49f4b8c0_53902_3bd7d97ba3139c197adbe686d8728a8e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;400&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: Results from compulsory education (#1.) replication study.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-results-from-health-insurance-2-replication-study&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Health insurance&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_health_insurance_hu613f7e53917fe269be1ce88eb77fc21b_50084_db3d51769d1136830b493f302b04d0a8.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_health_insurance_hu613f7e53917fe269be1ce88eb77fc21b_50084_5887a29f709deb71f404a5b5ba7d04d4.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_health_insurance_hu613f7e53917fe269be1ce88eb77fc21b_50084_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/hk_health_insurance_hu613f7e53917fe269be1ce88eb77fc21b_50084_db3d51769d1136830b493f302b04d0a8.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;396&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: Results from health insurance (#2.) replication study.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers make hundreds of decisions about data collection, preparation, and
analysis in their research. &amp;hellip;We find large differences in data preparation and analysis
decisions, many of which would not likely be reported in a publication. No two
replicators reported the same sample size. Statistical significance varied across
replications, and for one of the studies the effect&amp;rsquo;s sign varied as well. &lt;em&gt;The
standard deviation of estimates across replications was 3&amp;ndash;4 times the mean reported
standard error.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;h2 id=&#34;breznau-et-al-2022httpsosfiopreprintsmetaarxivcd5j9-----economics-statistics&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://osf.io/preprints/metaarxiv/cd5j9/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Breznau et al. (2022)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; economics, statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These authors pose the question: &lt;em&gt;does immigration reduce support for
social policies among the public&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer it, they recruited 162 participants across 73 teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each team was provided with a database of answers to a 6-question module on the
role of government in providing different social services, which is part of the
long-running International Social Survey Programme (ISSP). They were also provided
with a wide range of World Bank, OECD, and immigration data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-variation-in-average-marginal-effect-ame-across-73-teams-testing-the-same-hypothesis-with-the-same-data-ame-point-estimate-and-confidence-interval-for-each-team&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Variation in AME&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/breznau_AME_hudff59ae9cfb36d6ff6cae1eec6b9b4d0_167941_58f07cd358dace17379381d4fdbc2b01.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/breznau_AME_hudff59ae9cfb36d6ff6cae1eec6b9b4d0_167941_25d85ce1a5be31be26ea2254995ddad8.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/breznau_AME_hudff59ae9cfb36d6ff6cae1eec6b9b4d0_167941_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/breznau_AME_hudff59ae9cfb36d6ff6cae1eec6b9b4d0_167941_58f07cd358dace17379381d4fdbc2b01.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;455&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: Variation in Average Marginal Effect (AME) across 73 teams testing the same hypothesis with the same data. AME, point estimate, and Confidence Interval for each team.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;major research steps explain at most 2.6% of total variance in effect sizes and
10% of the deviance in subjective conclusions. Expertise, prior beliefs and attitudes
explain even less. &lt;em&gt;Each generated model was unique, which points to a vast universe
of research design variability normally hidden from view&lt;/em&gt; in the presentation, consumption,
and perhaps even creation of scientific results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sognnaes-et-al-2021httpswwwnaturecomarticless41558-021-01206-3-----emissions-integrated-assessment-modelling&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41558-021-01206-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Sognnaes et al. (2021)&lt;/a&gt; &amp;mdash; emissions, integrated assessment modelling&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors develop explicit post-2030 projections of &lt;em&gt;CO2 mitigation efforts&lt;/em&gt;.
They employ two different formulations to generate emissions-mitigation scenarios:
(i) continuing &lt;em&gt;rates&lt;/em&gt; of emissions-intensity reduction, i.e. emissions per unit of GDP, and
(ii) scaling of carbon prices in proportion to per capita GDP growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whereas in many studies and applications, scenario pathways are identified through
&amp;lsquo;backcasting&amp;rsquo; from future climate targets, Sognnaes et al. (2021) employ two formulations
of near-term mitigation efforts &amp;mdash; current policies (CPs) and nationally determined
contributions (NDCs) &amp;mdash; to which they apply the above-mentioned (i) and (ii) long-term
emissions-mitigation extensions beyond 2030. This results in a 2x2 matrix of combinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They then simulate forward emissions pathways using a diverse set of &lt;em&gt;seven&lt;/em&gt; Integrated
Assessment Models (IAMs):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jgcri.github.io/gcam-doc/overview.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Global Change Analysis Model (GCAM)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ucl.ac.uk/energy-models/models/tiam-ucl&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The TIMES Integrated Assessment Model (TIAM)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.imperial.ac.uk/muse-energy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ModUlar energy system Simulation Environment (MUSE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.i2am-paris.eu/detailed_model_doc/42&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;FortyTwo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10287-007-0047-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The General Equilibrium Model of International-National Interactions between Economy, Energy, and the Environment (GEMINI-E3)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s10584-020-02664-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Intertemporal Computable Equilibrium System &amp;ndash; eXtended Public Sector (ICES-XPS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.e3me.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Energy-Environment-Economy Macro-Econometric model (E3ME)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results of these simulations are summarised in the following two figures.
















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-global-energy-co2-emissions-to-2050-in-cp-scenarios-shaded-areas-show-emissions-spanned-by-cp_price-and-cp_intensity-scenarios-for-each-model-and-coloured-bars-show-2050-ranges-2045-value-for-fortytwo-which-has-only-intensity-scenarios-markers-above-bars-show-baseline-values-in-2050-in-2045-for-fortytwo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Global energy CO2 emissions; based on current policy&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_CP_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_76385_ef80762fff4df053b78c21dc2e699117.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_CP_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_76385_01088897983bbb97a296efa8634eb9b8.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_CP_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_76385_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_CP_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_76385_ef80762fff4df053b78c21dc2e699117.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;533&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: Global energy CO2 emissions to 2050 in CP scenarios. Shaded areas show emissions spanned by CP_Price and CP_Intensity scenarios for each model, and coloured bars show 2050 ranges (2045 value for FortyTwo, which has only intensity scenarios). Markers above bars show baseline values in 2050 (in 2045 for FortyTwo).
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-global-energy-co2-emissions-to-2050-in-ndc-scenarios-shaded-areas-show-emissions-spanned-by-ndc_price-and-ndc_intensity-scenarios-for-each-model-and-coloured-bars-show-2050-ranges-2045-value-for-fortytwo-which-has-only-intensity-scenarios-markers-above-bars-show-baseline-values-in-2050-in-2045-for-fortytwo&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Global energy CO2 emissions; based on nationally defined contributions&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_NDC_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_80208_9672c26c3c1e4d174dce206d2594ff76.webp 400w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_NDC_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_80208_f05571abe175b88f6520ecc463369933.webp 760w,
               /challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_NDC_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_80208_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/abundance-of-choice/Sognnaes_NDC_hub0bb520fec4b99b4f6ba5228d24253fb_80208_9672c26c3c1e4d174dce206d2594ff76.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;527&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Figure: Global energy CO2 emissions to 2050 in NDC scenarios. Shaded areas show emissions spanned by NDC_Price and NDC_Intensity scenarios for each model, and coloured bars show 2050 ranges (2045 value for FortyTwo, which has only intensity scenarios). Markers above bars show baseline values in 2050 (in 2045 for FortyTwo).
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The authors&amp;rsquo; conclusions parallel those of the &amp;lsquo;many analysts, one dataset&amp;rsquo; studies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip; &lt;em&gt;the model used has a larger impact on results than the method used to extend mitigation effort forward,&lt;/em&gt;
which in turn has a larger impact on results than whether CPs or NDCs are assumed in 2030.
The answer to where emissions are headed &amp;hellip; might therefore depend
more on the choice of models used and the post-2030 assumptions than on the 2030 target
assumed. This renders estimates of temperature consequences of NDCs and CPs sensitive to study design
and &lt;em&gt;highlights the importance of using a diversity of models and extension methods to capture this uncertainty.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;h2 id=&#34;synopsis&#34;&gt;Synopsis&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These studies have explicit selection criteria to ensure that they recruit only competent
researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to studies of this nature, the &amp;ldquo;degrees of freedom&amp;rdquo; inherent in empirical
analysis were not fully appreciated by researchers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than abundance of choice, these studies reveal a vast universe of previously hidden
research-design and analysis-operationalisation variability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt; 
&lt;br&gt; 
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circularity problem</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/circularity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 17:05:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/circularity-problem/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unconditional forecasts of global temperature alone have an ambiguous interpretation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose a forecast portends a small global temperature anomaly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are future temperatures low because CO2 emissions will be tamed aggressively, or
because climate turns out to be much less sensitive to atmospheric CO2 concentrations
than currently believed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Predictions of e.g. global temperature alone lack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the pathway of the policy variable (CO2 concentration), and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the relationship between the policy variable and the outcome variable (global temperature).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In monetary policy, the recommended-policy relationship between interest rates
(the policy variable) and inflation and the output gap (the targets of policy)
is known as the &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.atlantafed.org/cqer/research/taylor-rule&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Taylor rule&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no &amp;lsquo;Taylor rule&amp;rsquo; for emissions policy over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;not for one country, and certaintly not across all top emitters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the net Zero commitment formally moves toward this, but statements of intention
do not necessarily translate into operational, enforced regulations in all countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can climate-risk information providers resolve this circularity problem?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data gaps</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/data-gaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 17:00:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/data-gaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data gaps are particularly substantial and pressing for &lt;em&gt;forward-looking&lt;/em&gt; risk information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And where forward-looking information exists, it is largely based on (i) announced intentions, or
(ii) scenarios for which relative likelihood information currently does not exist. Moreover,
numerous organizations have created their own scenario sets. Users of forward-looking
information do not know how to evaluate the range of different scenarios, and which
scenarios should be given more attention, and which less attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ngfs-2021-progress-report-on-bridging-data-gapshttpswwwngfsnetsitesdefaultfilesmediasdocumentsprogress_report_on_bridging_data_gapspdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ngfs.net/sites/default/files/medias/documents/progress_report_on_bridging_data_gaps.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NGFS (2021) Progress report on bridging data gaps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stakeholders report the need for more forward-looking data and granular data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While acknowledging the need for a forward-looking perspective, stakeholders still
largely rely on metrics that are backward-looking in nature. &amp;hellip;Stakeholders have
pointed out that they cannot rely on such metrics alone. They also need to finance
transition and analyse the pathways to climate goals over time by also using forwardlooking metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ngfs-2022-final-report-on-bridging-data-gapshttpswwwngfsnetsitesdefaultfilesmediasdocumentsfinal_report_on_bridging_data_gapspdf&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ngfs.net/sites/default/files/medias/documents/final_report_on_bridging_data_gaps.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;NGFS (2022) Final report on bridging data gaps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[Credit Rating Agencies] also reported that the biggest gaps are in the forward-looking data, which
are essential for consistency of accounting treatments and scenario assumptions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importance of forward-looking data is stressed by the stakeholders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommendation 3: Develop well-defined and decision-useful metrics, and methodological
standards. To further advance this goal, there is a need to substantially increase the
harmonisation of forward-looking metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Incentives</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/bad-incentives/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 13:27:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/challenge/bad-incentives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Climate Service Provider&lt;/em&gt; (CSP) industry is growing rapidly to meet demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this drive to meet growing demand, a number of issues rooted in adverse incentives have been overlooked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #1:&lt;/strong&gt; Price competition, asymmetric information, and multi-decadal &amp;lsquo;discovery time&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“In many ways, the marketplace is operating on blind faith in model validation and the
professional competence in applying those models,” with some “products and services
that may be operating outside of the bounds of scientific merit” (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aay8442&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Keenan, 2019, &amp;ldquo;A climate
intelligence arms race in financial markets&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If providers of climate forecasts are paid upfront irrespective of accuracy, you don’t need to
be an economist to spot the problem with that arrangement.” &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/lums/news/how-prediction-markets-could-improve-climate-risk-policies-and-investment-decisions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Mark Roulston&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #2:&lt;/strong&gt; Possibility of &amp;lsquo;results-led&amp;rsquo; research. Parallels with Credit-Rating Agencies pre-2007!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #3:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;lsquo;public good&amp;rsquo; nature of much climate-risk information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If privately funded: how to restrict access (to private-good or club-good status) so that
individual organisations can benefit from funding the development of climate-risk information?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If publicly funded: how to fund this very applied type of research, in the required
frequency of updates, when the output isn’t in the form of a piece of work suitable for a
high-ranked academic journal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issue #4:&lt;/strong&gt; The &amp;lsquo;downscaling&amp;rsquo; from global models is more questionable on multi-decadal horizons of
climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prcisions vs. accuracy, and &amp;lsquo;false precision&amp;rsquo;. For box-ticking exercises low accuracy might not matter.
But for informing societally transformative policies, regulations, and business-investment decisions,
false precision and low accuracy are fundamentally problematic in their consequences: misallocation of effort, resource, and painful sacrifice (which is on the horizon).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How &#39;prediction markets&#39; could improve climate risk policies and investment decisions</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/prediction-markets-improve-policies-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/prediction-markets-improve-policies-decisions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A market-led approach could be key to guiding policy, research and business decisions about future climate risks, &lt;a href=&#34;https://rdcu.be/cUMH6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a new study outlines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Published today in the journal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/nclimate/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nature Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;, the paper from academics at the Universities of Lancaster and Exeter details how expert &amp;lsquo;prediction markets&amp;rsquo; could improve the climate-risk forecasts that guide key business and regulatory decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organisations now appreciate that they have to consider climate risks within their strategic plans &amp;mdash; whether that relates to physical risks to buildings and sites, or risks associated with transitioning to achieve net zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the forward-looking information needed to inform these strategic decisions is limited, the researchers say.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/lums/people/kim-kaivanto&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr Kim Kaivanto&lt;/a&gt;, a co-author from Lancaster University’s Department of Economics and a member of the Climate Risk and Uncertainty Collective Intelligence Aggregation Laboratory (CRUCIAL), said: “The institutional arrangements under which climate-risk information is currently provided mirrors the incentive problems and conflicts of interest that prevailed in the credit-rating industry prior to the 2007/8 financial crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In order to make sense of emissions scenarios and to support planning and decision-making, organisations have a pressing need for this type of forward-looking expert risk information.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Understanding climate risks requires diverse and complementary expertise from political science, economics and policy, as well as country-specific knowledge on the major emitters. Prediction markets incentivise and reward participants with distinct expertise and information to come forward – and they offer a level playing field for experts from these complementary fields of expertise.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Roulston, one of the Exeter University co-authors said, &amp;ldquo;If providers of climate forecasts are paid upfront irrespective of accuracy, you don’t need to be an economist to spot the problem with that arrangement.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In their paper, &amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rdcu.be/cUMH6&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prediction-market innovations can improve climate-risk forecasts&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo; the authors detail how expert &amp;lsquo;prediction markets&amp;rsquo; can help overcome the structural problems and shortfalls in the provision of forward-looking climate-risk information &amp;mdash; something that will become more vital as the demand for long-range climate information increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prediction markets are designed to incentivise those with important information to come forward, and facilitate the aggregation of information through the buying and selling of contracts that yield a fixed payoff if the specified event occurs. An outcome of interest – such as average CO2 concentration in the year 2040, for example – is partitioned into intervals. Expert participants compare the results of their own modelling with the prices of these intervals, and purchase or sell claims on these intervals if their model suggests the price is too low or too high.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a well-designed market such as Lancaster University’s AGORA prediction-market platform, the price of a contract can be interpreted as the market-based probability of the event happening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These kinds of long-range markets have not been established to date due, in part, to regulatory obstacles. However, the researchers believe the markets can be designed to overcome these obstacles by avoiding the &amp;lsquo;pay-to-play&amp;rsquo; aspect of existing prediction markets in which the losses of less-well-informed individuals fund the winnings of better-informed individuals. Instead, markets can be structured as vehicles for distributing research funding to experts and modellers in a manner that is consistent with the principles of effective altruism: an initial stake provided by a sponsor is distributed to participants in accordance with the quality and quantity of information they bring into the market through their trading activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They add that access to participation in the markets would need to have selection criteria to ensure diversity of views and a range of expertise to ensure they are able to aggregate diverse sources of information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper’s authors are Kim Kaivanto of Lancaster University, and Mark Roulston, Todd Kaplan and Brett Day of the University of Exeter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original version of this article appeared as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/news/how-prediction-markets-could-improve-climate-risk-policies-and-investment-decisions&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How ‘prediction markets’ could improve climate risk policies and investment decisions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction-market innovations can improve climate-risk forecasts</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/publication/prediction-market-innovations-can-improve-climate-risk-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:01:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/publication/prediction-market-innovations-can-improve-climate-risk-forecasts/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction market platform donated to LU</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/prediction-market-platform-donated-to-lu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 18:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/prediction-market-platform-donated-to-lu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This enables researchers to host expert prediction markets for climate-risk outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Kim Kaivanto, Senior Lecturer in Economics at Lancaster University Management School, co-organised a workshop at Woburn House, London, earlier this year, bringing industry and academic figures together to discuss the problems involved in the current provision of climate-risk information, and the ways in which prediction markets can help overcome those problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said: “We are extremely pleased to be carrying forward this initiative to run expert prediction markets for climate risk outcomes. To make sense of emissions scenarios and to support planning and decision-making, both public and private sector organisations have a pressing need for this type of forward-looking expert risk information.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hivemind was spun out of UK research-based investment manager Winton Group in 2018. Winton, which remains a majority shareholder of Hivemind, created the original version of the AGORA prediction market platform, which Hivemind further developed and tested. Hivemind’s other shareholders include Fidelity International Strategic Ventures, and Barclays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hivemind’s shareholders are donating the IP and codebase for AGORA to Lancaster University for a joint initiative with Exeter University to use prediction markets for forecasting longer-range climate risks, and even as an efficient mechanism for performance-driven allocation of funding for applied climate research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGORA has previously been used to run prediction markets for seasonal temperatures and rainfall, El Niño events, hurricane activity, and crop yields. Experts from academia and the private sector took part in these markets, which generated probability forecasts that synthesised their knowledge and evolved as new information became available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prediction markets have characteristics which are useful for long-range climate-risk forecasting. They incentivise and reward participants with distinct expertise and information to come forward. They also provide a level playing field for experts from different — yet complementary — fields of expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding emissions pathways requires diverse and complementary expertise from political science, economics and policy, as well as country-specific knowledge for the largest emitters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AGORA Prediction Market platform can integrate this expertise with that of climate scientists, whose models are conditioned on emissions scenarios. Also, as the markets are being run to generate information as a public good, rather than for private profit, the incentives to skew evaluations to suit any one organisation are mitigated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mark Roulston, who oversaw the development of AGORA and is now working on the climate initiative, said: “The prediction market approach should interest governments, companies and philanthropists who want to fund climate research from diverse sources in an efficient and performance-driven way.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hiveminds-shareholders&#34;&gt;Hivemind&amp;rsquo;s shareholders:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Winton Group (“Winton”) is a research-based investment management company with a specialist focus on statistical and mathematical inference in financial markets. The firm’s quantitative investment strategies are implemented systematically across thousands of securities, spanning the world&amp;rsquo;s major liquid asset classes. Founded by David Harding in 1997, Winton manages assets on behalf some of the world’s largest institutional investors. For more information, please visit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.winton.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.winton.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-fidelity-international&#34;&gt;About Fidelity International:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fidelity International offers investment solutions and services and retirement expertise to more than 2.5 million customers globally. As a privately held, purpose-driven company with a 50-year heritage, they think generationally and invest for the long term. Operating in more than 25 countries and with $767.6 billion in total assets, their clients range from central banks, sovereign wealth funds, large corporates, financial institutions, insurers and wealth managers, to private individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their Workplace &amp;amp; Personal Financial Health business provides individuals, advisers and employers with access to world-class investment choices, third-party solutions, administration services and pension guidance. Together with their Investment Solutions &amp;amp; Services business, they invest $574.9 billion on behalf of their clients. By combining their asset management expertise with their solutions for workplace and personal investing, they work together to build better financial futures. Data as of 31 March 2022. Read more at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fidelityinternational.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.fidelityinternational.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-barclays&#34;&gt;About Barclays:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barclays is a British universal bank. They are diversified by business, by different types of customer and client, and geography. Their businesses include consumer banking and payments operations around the world, as well as a top-tier, full service, global corporate and investment bank, all of which are supported by their service company which provides technology, operations and functional services across the Group.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared as &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/news/lancaster-university-obtains-new-climate-prediction-markets-platform&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lancaster University obtains new climate prediction markets platform &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CRUCIAL White Paper</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/publication/crucial-white-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jul 2022 00:01:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/publication/crucial-white-paper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;executive-summary&#34;&gt;Executive Summary&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;What?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Information markets use market-like 
mechanisms to elicit and aggregate 
information. Information markets are not 
designed to transfer ownership or risk but to 
exploit the proven ability of markets to 
discover and synthesize information. 
Information markets can solve the problems of 
aggregating diverse climate expertise and
aligning the incentives of providers. They
could become the primary mechanism for 
obtaining forward-looking expertise about 
climate-related risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Climate change is recognised as an important 
source of risk. Regulators now believe that 
climate-related risks pose, not only a threat to 
individual firms, but possibly to the stability of 
the financial system.
In 2017 the G20’s Task Force on Climate-Related Financial Disclosures (TCFD) 
published recommendations that firms should 
disclose forward-looking information about 
physical and transition climate-related risks. 
More than two thousand companies have 
voluntarily signed-up to these 
recommendations. Regulators and exchanges 
in many countries plan to make climate-related disclosures mandatory. These trends 
have created a demand for forward-looking 
information about climate, such as emissions 
pathways and changes in physical climate 
risks. Companies requiring this information 
are a nascent source of funding for applied 
climate research. They are particularly 
interested in the efficiency with which 
distributed information can be aggregated 
and communicated for use in decision making 
and risk management. 
The marketplace for climate information is 
diverse and fragmented. Relevant expertise 
exists in public agencies, academia, think 
tanks, as well as an emerging class of private 
companies known as climate service 
providers (CSPs). Given the long horizons 
involved, few providers have established track 
records, so it is difficult for users to evaluate 
their skill. Furthermore, most forecasts are 
offered with no warranty. This creates a 
situation in which bad forecasts can drive out 
good ones; a situation reminiscent of credit 
ratings for mortgage-backed securities in the 
run-up to the subprime crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;How?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
We propose a climate information exchange 
that hosts markets predicting climate-related 
variables. These variables will include high-level ones, such as global greenhouse gas 
concentrations, and more granular ones like
sea-level rise in specific locations. Market 
participants will include individuals and 
institutions with expertise across the range of 
disciplines relevant to climate forecasting, 
including meteorology, climatology, 
economics, social sciences, and policy. 
Participants will use on-platform credits 
representing a claim on a proportion of 
research funds distributed through the 
exchange. These funds will come from public, 
private, and philanthropic sources interested 
in effective altruism.
The exchange will use AGORA, developed by 
Hivemind Technologies Ltd. AGORA has been 
used to run expert information markets for 
seasonal forecasts, El Niño events, Atlantic 
hurricane activity, and crop yields. AGORA
solves several problems that have afflicted 
previous attempts to create information 
markets for climate: an automated market 
maker guarantees liquidity allowing markets 
to function in the absence of uninformed 
“noise” traders. AGORA supports very large 
outcome spaces, enabling consensus 
probability distributions to be extracted, not 
just probabilities for binary events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
Many of the markets will have horizons of 
more than a decade. The consensus forecasts 
generated will be a public good, to be 
distributed for free. There is a strong case for 
the exchange to be hosted by a university, 
which will become a hub for international 
climate expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why no climate warranties?</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/why-no-climate-warranties/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 18:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/why-no-climate-warranties/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The market for climate risk forecasts suffers from a problem economists call 
“asymmetric information”: the sellers of forecasts probably know more about their 
accuracy than the buyers. A short or medium range weather forecast can be verified 
in a couple of weeks, and reasonable statistics about their accuracy can be 
accumulated in a matter of months but, because a climate forecast might not verify 
for years or decades, buyers cannot usually use a forecaster’s track record to assess 
their accuracy. A market in which the quality of a product won’t be apparent for years 
is susceptible to “adverse selection”, which is economists’ way of saying it will be 
a magnet for charlatans. This creates a challenge for providers of climate forecasts 
who are competent and have invested in research and development to improve the accuracy: 
how can they persuade buyers that &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; are not charlatans?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Talk is cheap.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate service providers can emphasise their credentials and highlight the scientific 
effort that goes into their products; they might allow users to see how their models 
work &amp;mdash; although many users don’t have the expertise to assess the models, and if the 
seller uses proprietary models this might not be option anyway. The problem with these 
solutions is that “talk is cheap”, and it is difficult for a buyer to distinguish 
authentic expertise from slick marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economist George Akerlof, who won a Nobel Prize for his work on information 
asymmetries, explained the problem in a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/1879431&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;classic paper published in 1970&lt;/a&gt; which 
described the market for used cars. As with climate forecasts, it is difficult 
for the buyer of a used car to know its quality and, also like climate forecasts, 
a car is an infrequent purchase so there is little opportunity to accumulate much 
first-hand knowledge about the reliability of a seller. These attributes made the 
market for used cars attractive to less-than-reputable characters, creating the 
stereotype of the untrustworthy used-car dealer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Dealers offered warranties to differentiate themselves from competitors.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reputation of used-car dealers has improved since the 1970s, partly because 
the sector adopted one of the strategies for dealing with asymmetric information 
described by Akerlof: offering cash back warranties. In the U.K. used-car 
warranties became mandatory in 2015, but even before then, dealers offered 
warranties to differentiate themselves from competitors and enable them to 
charge higher prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A promise of a refund if a product fails can serve two distinct purposes: 
indemnifying the buyer for losses caused by the failure and providing a credible 
signal that the seller believes failure is unlikely. An inaccurate climate 
forecast may cause the user a loss far above the price they paid for the forecast: 
for example, they may build sea defences that are too low, or too high. While a 
forecast provider might not be able to indemnify the user against all costs, 
they can still offer a refund to signal their confidence in the accuracy of the 
forecast. The credibility of the signal is determined, not by whether the refund 
will compensate the user, but whether it will be painful for the provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climate forecasts, generally, are not categorically right or wrong: they are 
probabilistic forecasts — or they should be — in which probabilities are assigned 
to specified outcomes. How could the terms of a refund be structured for this type 
of product? There is a literature on this subject going back 70 years, when &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.ametsoc.org/view/journals/mwre/78/1/1520-0493_1950_078_0001_vofeit_2_0_co_2.xml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Glenn 
Brier introduced a quadratic scoring rule for assessing probability forecasts&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/2984087&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;I.J. Good suggested the logarithmic scoring rule as a way to reward forecasters.&lt;/a&gt; 
Since then more work has been done on the concept of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.stat.washington.edu/raftery/Research/PDF/Gneiting2007jasa.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“proper scoring rules”&lt;/a&gt; for 
incentivizing forecasters. More recently, proper scoring rules have been &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/43189651&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;suggested 
as the basis for incentives that screen the views of informed and uninformed experts 
when only a single forecast is being made.&lt;/a&gt; There are subtleties to be appreciated, 
and pitfalls to avoid, but in principle a proper scoring rule could be used to 
evaluate the quality of a probabilistic forecast and determine the refund to which 
the buyer is entitled. This can only be done when the actual outcome becomes known, 
which in some cases may be more than twenty years after the forecast is made. Some 
people might think that providing a warranty on a timescale of decades is 
unrealistic but other industries do it: e.g., 10-year structural warranties for 
new houses or the lifetime warranties offered by high-end manufacturers that can 
be claimed decades after a product is purchased. It is also analogous to deferring 
bonuses in the finance industry. Climate service providers unwilling to expose 
themselves to some risk on climatic timescales are arguably in the wrong business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“A well-structured warranty can be used to communicate how much confidence a forecast provider has.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The information asymmetry in the market for climate forecasts is at least as bad 
as the one for used cars, so why aren’t warranties commonplace? There is no need 
for a regulator to force forecasters to provide warranties. As with used-cars, 
any provider is free to unilaterally offer warranties to differentiate themselves. 
One possibility is that few climate service providers have enough confidence in 
their forecasts to give warranties. However, a probabilistic forecast combined 
with a well-structured warranty can be used to communicate how much (or little) 
confidence a forecast provider has, and this is information that the forecast user 
should want. An alternative explanation is that there is little demand from buyers 
for sellers to provide a credible signal of their confidence in forecast accuracy. 
This interpretation is consistent with the view that buyers of climate risk 
information use it to satisfy regulators, auditors, or other stakeholders, but 
aren’t really worried about its accuracy; they just need it to give them “plausible 
deniability”. Worse than indifference, is the possibility that some organisations 
&lt;em&gt;want&lt;/em&gt; inaccurate forecasts. Back in the early 2000s, the issuers of mortgage-backed 
securities didn’t want accurate credit ratings for them, they wanted top-notch 
ratings, even if these did not reflect the true risk of default. These issuers would 
play rating agencies off against each other to get their desired ratings, and the 
ensuing proliferation of mis-rated securities contributed to the subprime crisis of 
2007/08.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;End-users of climate risk forecasts who care about accuracy should signal their 
commitment by being prepared to pay more for forecasts that come with a warranty. 
This will motivate reputable providers to offer such guarantees, thus differentiating 
themselves from less able providers. Without a strategy to combat asymmetric 
information about climate forecasts it is possible that climate service providers 
will gradually acquire the reputation of 1970s used-car dealers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared on Medium as &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Mark_Roulston/why-no-climate-warranties-c32abe91b181&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Why no climate warranties?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prediction Markets for Climate Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/event/woburn-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2022 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/event/woburn-house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/woburn-house/foot_hue389a492d2a1656f1a3c5aaf695d06b2_67715_bbaf7be3e1d055acc9000e42308a8640.webp 400w,
               /event/woburn-house/foot_hue389a492d2a1656f1a3c5aaf695d06b2_67715_211850a605332e1c963f20259709b4d8.webp 760w,
               /event/woburn-house/foot_hue389a492d2a1656f1a3c5aaf695d06b2_67715_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/event/woburn-house/foot_hue389a492d2a1656f1a3c5aaf695d06b2_67715_bbaf7be3e1d055acc9000e42308a8640.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;144&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;industry-and-academic-leaders-come-together-for-climate-risk-workshop&#34;&gt;Industry and academic leaders come together for climate risk workshop&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An event co-organised by a Lancaster University Management School economist brought industry and academic figures together to discuss the links between investment strategies and climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Kim Kaivanto (Economics) was part of the team behind the Workshop on Prediction Markets for Climate Risk, held at Woburn House, in London.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers and academics with expertise in market mechanisms and climate risk from Lancaster University, Oxford University, the University of Exeter, Imperial College London, the University of Reading and the London School of Economics attended the event online and in-person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were joined by representatives of organisations concerned about the accuracy of the climate information they use for decision making, risk management and risk disclosure. These included Aviva, Gallagher Re, Axa XL, BNP Paribas, Premetrica, Economics for the Environment Consultancy, National Bank of Belgium, Weather Logistics Ltd., Global Assoc Risk Professionals, Insight Investment, APG Asset Management, Jupiter Intelligence, Federated Hermes, and Smarkets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr Kaivanto said: “Many planning and investment decisions require an understanding of how future climate change will manifest itself. There are many sources of information and expertise, but decision-makers face significant difficulties in accessing, interpreting, and appraising it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This workshop provided the opportunity for academia and finance professionals to discuss how we can establish a UK-based prediction market exchange that will seek to deliver robust and publicly available climate forecasts. It could serve as a mechanism to fund research that targets the highest priority climate risks of sponsoring institutions in an incentive compatible way for providers.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his presentation at Woburn House, Dr Kaivanto outlined structural issues with the climate risk information and forecast markets, including how the decadal “discovery times” required to ascertain the accuracy of climate forecasts creates an information asymmetry in which providers are likely to know more about the quality of the forecasts than users. This asymmetry makes the market vulnerable to adverse selection in which low-quality forecasts drive out higher-quality forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also discussed the potential risks of relying on single models and providers for climate risk assessment, and the circularity problem in climate prediction, and how it might be solved by allowing forecasters to make predictions of climate conditioned on greenhouse gas concentrations, which is possible using two-dimensional, joint-outcome markets (e.g. CO2 concentration and global temperature anomaly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The session concluded that participants in prediction markets should be seen as sources of information who are rewarded for impounding their information into prediction market prices, not as sources of revenue for the market maker, or for better-informed or quicker market participants. Selection of participants – potentially restricted to individuals or organisations (academic, private sector or NGOs) – would allow for a diverse and credible pool of expertise, adding to the credibility of the markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participants also concluded that the information the markets would generate would have the attributes of a ‘public good’: non-rival and non-excludable, with funding typically from governments, philanthropic foundations, or consortia of end-users – the latter of whom could limit access to the information, for more of a ‘club good’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This report on the workshop originally appeared &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lancaster.ac.uk/lums/news/industry-and-academic-leaders-come-together-for-climate-risk-workshop&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cost witout benefit</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/cost-without-benefit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 18:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/cost-without-benefit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 1970, the economist George Akerlof published what would become a classic paper called, 
“&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/1879431&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Market for Lemons: Quality Uncertainty and Market Mechanisms.&lt;/a&gt;” The “lemons” he was 
referring to were low-quality used cars. His insight was that, in markets where buyers 
cannot evaluate products, they will not pay a premium for purported high quality. This, 
in turn, will give sellers little incentive to provide high quality products. Consequently, 
the average quality of products in the market declines, further reducing the amount buyers 
are willing to pay. In economics jargon an “information asymmetry” between buyers and sellers 
results in “adverse selection”. The process identified by Akerlof is now a textbook example 
of market failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A buyer of short-range weather forecasts does not need to know about meteorology to evaluate them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The used car market is not the only one susceptible to the “lemon” problem. (Ironically, in the market for actual lemons, buyers can easily assess freshness and taste). A rapidly growing market that is also vulnerable is the one for information about long-range climate risks. A buyer of short-range weather forecasts does not need to know about meteorology to evaluate them. They just need to know some statistics and be able to collect a sufficiently large sample of forecasts and subsequent outcomes to estimate the skill of the provider. For forecasts 1–2 days ahead, this sample might be obtained in a matter of months. However, companies increasingly need forecasts of climate-related risks on horizons of years, and even decades. Obviously, on these time scales, waiting to see how forecasts turn out before choosing a provider is not practical. Some providers want to keep their models and methods proprietary, but even with full transparency it can be hard for non-specialists to judge their quality. When a market has these characteristics, buyers need to be alert to the danger that bad products will crowd out good ones.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are theoretical reasons why the quality of climate information may deteriorate, but is 
there evidence of this happening in practice? In 2019, an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.aay8442&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;article in Science&lt;/a&gt; suggested that 
some climate information products might be “&amp;hellip;operating outside of the bounds of scientific merit” 
and, if you work in the field of climate risk, you have probably heard stories of providers 
pushing precision and granularity beyond what is scientifically plausible. But is there systematic 
evidence that some climate information has a lemon flavour?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortcomings in long-range climate-related predictions might not become apparent for years but there are already indications of problems. Hain et al. recently looked at six different metrics of firm-level exposure to physical climate risks. Three of the measures, from TruCost (part of S&amp;amp;P), Carbon4 Finance and South Pole, were based on the output of climate models, while the other three, from Truvalue Labs (part of FactSet) and two academic groups were constructed by analysing the content of social media, earnings calls and 10-K filings. The correlations between the metrics were generally low, both overall and within specific sectors. Indeed, after allowing for the multiplicity of correlations tested, there were arguably no significant correlations between different metrics. Think about this for a moment: six metrics all claiming to measure the same thing, or at least to be proxies for the same thing, yet they don’t correlate with each other. Even the most generous interpretation implies that most of the metrics contain little information about the common factor they claim to measure. Perhaps one of the metrics is a good measure, but which one? Perhaps none of the metrics are informative. Consider an analogy in which there are six different blood tests to measure the same substance, but when hundreds of subjects are given all six tests there is no correlation between the results. Would a doctor base clinical decisions on any of these tests? Would a medical regulator allow such a situation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time the accuracy becomes apparent all those involved are likely to have moved on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem of information asymmetry between buyers and sellers might be compounded when the buyers of climate information are not concerned with the accuracy of the information either. Much of the demand for forward-looking climate information is driven by regulators and shareholders expecting firms to disclose their climate-related risks. The exercise is one of “putting numbers in boxes”, and by the time the accuracy of the numbers becomes apparent, all those involved are likely to have moved on. This is not conducive to accurate disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, you might protest that there are many people involved in climate-risk who want to provide accurate and rigorous information that is supported by science, and there are many people who want such information to make accurate disclosures of risk to shareholders. This is true, but it misses the point: the problems in the market for climate-risk information are structural. The used-car market did not become a market for lemons because it was populated by untrustworthy salesmen; it attracted and created the stereotype of the used-car salesman because of its intrinsic information asymmetries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If information asymmetry and the potential for adverse selection in the market for forward-looking climate information is not addressed, it is likely that more evidence will accumulate that undermines the credibility of climate-related risk disclosures. This will make mandatory disclosures a cost to businesses without any offsetting benefit to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared on Medium as &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@Mark_Roulston/how-climate-related-risk-disclosures-could-become-a-cost-without-a-benefit-e74085062e31&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How climate-related risk disclosures could become a cost without a benefit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AGORA hurricane prediction markets settled</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 00:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-1-the-evolution-of-the-agora-prediction-market-forecast-for-the-total-number-of-hurricanes-during-the-2020-atlantic-hurricane-season&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Atlantic hurricanes during 2020 season&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled/featured_hu0168a37685d70d935606e1bf3b15cb70_254126_6e9047dee3b325fbe710598e6757d7a0.webp 400w,
               /post/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled/featured_hu0168a37685d70d935606e1bf3b15cb70_254126_5c319f3f81220d90d277eaed35599940.webp 760w,
               /post/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled/featured_hu0168a37685d70d935606e1bf3b15cb70_254126_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled/featured_hu0168a37685d70d935606e1bf3b15cb70_254126_6e9047dee3b325fbe710598e6757d7a0.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;380&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 1&lt;/strong&gt;: The evolution of the AGORA prediction market forecast for the total number of hurricanes during the 2020 Atlantic hurricane season.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 30 the 2020 Atlantic hurricane season came to an end and Hivemind settled prediction markets forecasting how many hurricanes there would be and how many would make landfall over the U.S.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2020 hurricane season was one of the most active ever seen. There were 30 named storms, beating the 2005 record of 28. Of the 30 storms, 13 achieved hurricane strength and 6 of those made landfall over the U.S., with a further 4 making landfall over Central America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of its participation in the Fifth Cohort of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://lloydslab.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Lloyd’s Lab InsurTech accelerator&lt;/a&gt;, Hivemind ran hurricane prediction markets on its AGORA prediction market platform. Twenty experts in meteorology and statistical climatology from academia and the private sector took part. The market opened in August when the season was underway and three hurricanes had already occurred. Forecasts from groups at &lt;a href=&#34;https://tropical.colostate.edu/forecasting.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Colorado State University&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tropicalstormrisk.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Tropical Storm Risk&lt;/a&gt; were for an active season with 12 and 10 hurricanes respectively. This information was immediately priced into the market, with the expected number of hurricanes jumping from the climatological average of 6 to around 10 on opening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the season progressed the market expectation fluctuated in response to the formation of new storms — increasing to 12 when three hurricanes formed in the space of a week and falling back during a two week period with no hurricanes. It rose again as a succession of storms formed that meant, as in 2005, the National Hurricane Centre exhausted their &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nhc.noaa.gov/aboutnames.shtml&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;alphabetized storm names&lt;/a&gt; and had to resort to Greek letters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hailiang Du, Assistant Professor of Statistics at Durham University, finished top in the market for the total number of hurricanes. “I usually looked at NOAA 5-day and 2-day outlooks, sometimes also European model runs as well as Canadian models,” explained Professor Du, “I tried to aggregate the model information together to form my own forecast probability distribution.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AGORA hurricane prediction markets demonstrate how prediction markets assimilate new information as it becomes available. Unlike surveys, which provide a snapshot of views at a point in time, prediction markets allow participants to update their positions in real time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGORA prediction markets could be used to generate pre-season forecasts of hurricane activity. Markets for multiple years ahead could also produce consensus predictions of the impact climate change may have on storm frequencies and intensities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original version of this article appeared as &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/hvmd/agora-hurricane-prediction-markets-settled-4841d85b602b&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;AGORA hurricane prediction markets settled&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How good are AGORA forecasts?</title>
      <link>https://www.crucialab.net/post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2020 18:41:05 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.crucialab.net/post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Calibration means the frequency of events matches their predicted probabilities”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two desirable characteristics that probability forecasts should have:
&lt;em&gt;calibration&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;sharpness&lt;/em&gt;. Calibration means that the frequency of events matches
their predicted probabilities while sharpness refers to how often predicted probabilities
are close to 0% or 100% for binary forecasts or how narrow the forecast distribution is
for a numerical value. Making sharp forecasts is trivial if you don’t care about
calibration, so in this blog we will investigate whether forecasts produced by AGORA
are calibrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I predict a 90% chance of an event occurring and it doesn’t happen then I am not
wrong because I allowed for a 10% chance of it not happening. If, however, I repeatedly
predict a 90% chance of things occurring and they keep failing to happen you will lose
confidence in my ability as a forecaster. This is because my forecasts are not well
calibrated. Calibration means the frequency of events matches their predicted
probabilities: for example, if you record all the times I said there was a 60%
chance of something occurring, that something should have happened 60% of those times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-1-an-illustration-of-the-percentiles-of-a-predicted-probability-distribution-if-the-predicted-distribution-is-well-calibrated-there-is-a-5-chance-the-actual-value-will-fall-below-the-5th-percentile-a-25-chance-it-will-fall-below-the-25th-percentile-etc&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Normal distribution&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/normald_hu13e4b697727ee04d039eeb86276590db_40642_fc503aa7bd30259b584e0a144a443119.webp 400w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/normald_hu13e4b697727ee04d039eeb86276590db_40642_f62d7ff834d5460c18e741deda1c933b.webp 760w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/normald_hu13e4b697727ee04d039eeb86276590db_40642_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/normald_hu13e4b697727ee04d039eeb86276590db_40642_fc503aa7bd30259b584e0a144a443119.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;632&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 1&lt;/strong&gt;: An illustration of the percentiles of a predicted probability distribution. If the predicted distribution is well calibrated there is a 5% chance the actual value will fall below the 5th percentile, a 25% chance it will fall below the 25th percentile etc.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For well calibrated forecasts of numerical values half the time the actual value
should fall below the median (50th percentile) of the predicted distribution and
half the time it should fall above it. Similarly, the actual value should fall
below the 10th percentile of the predicted distribution in 10 per cent of cases,
below the 20th percentile in 20 per cent of cases, and so on. These percentiles
are illustrated in Figure 1. If we plot the percentage of forecasts for which the
actual value falls below a given percentile of the forecast distribution we should
get a diagonal line. Because we have a finite number of forecasts there will be
deviations from this line, even if the forecasts are perfectly calibrated, with
the size of the deviations shrinking as the number of forecasts used in the analysis
increases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-2-a-calibration-plot-for-23-agora-probabilistic-at-a-normalized-lead-time-of-075-after-25-of-the-time-between-opening-and-settlement-has-elapsed-the-grey-envelope-shows-the-amount-of-deviation-from-the-diagonal-that-can-be-expected-if-the-23-forecasts-were-perfectly-calibrated-the-plot-is-consistent-with-agora-forecasts-being-well-calibrated&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;0.75 lead-time calibration plot&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead75_hu0a8c8bbdc336901a73d82ceab9f87aa1_199466_08efc9f35ac03b8a8b2260125e2bc06c.webp 400w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead75_hu0a8c8bbdc336901a73d82ceab9f87aa1_199466_cba2f8ed7de98267aee30bcb80bb29eb.webp 760w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead75_hu0a8c8bbdc336901a73d82ceab9f87aa1_199466_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead75_hu0a8c8bbdc336901a73d82ceab9f87aa1_199466_08efc9f35ac03b8a8b2260125e2bc06c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;759&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 2&lt;/strong&gt;: A calibration plot for 23 AGORA probabilistic at a normalized lead time of 0.75 (after 25% of the time between opening and settlement has elapsed). The grey envelope shows the amount of deviation from the diagonal that can be expected if the 23 forecasts were perfectly calibrated. The plot is consistent with AGORA forecasts being well calibrated.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When performing a calibration analysis we need to choose a forecast lead time. If
all the forecasts in the analysis are of the same type then this is straightforward:
for example, we might want to check the calibration of rainfall forecasts 3 days
before the target date. If, however, we are dealing with different types of forecasts,
choosing a common lead time might not make sense: Harold Wilson said that, “A week
is a long time in politics”, but a week is no time at all in climate prediction. We
will express all lead times relative to the duration of the prediction market: A
normalized lead time of 0.25 means that a quarter of the time between opening and
settlement remains until settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figure 2 shows the calibration of 23 AGORA forecasts. The forecasts included in
the analysis were all the public markets that have been run on the AGORA platform
with cash incentives for participants. This includes predictions of monthly UK
temperature, values of an El Niño-Southern Oscillation index and monthly totals
of COVID-19 cases in the U.S. The yellow line follows the diagonal with some
deviations but the deviations lie within the grey envelope, which indicates how
much deviation would occur with 23 perfectly calibrated forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Figures 3 and 4 show the calibration plot for normalized lead time of 0.50 and
0.25. The plot for 0.25 suggests the frequency of the actual value falling below
the median is only about 30% although this deviation is still consistent with
calibrated forecasts due to the relatively small number of forecasts in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-3-as-figure-2-but-for-a-normalized-lead-time-of-05&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;0.50 lead-time calibration plot&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead50_hu31b9b0587f2695c03240d66e69d5aef4_27727_9e1685bca80c36af472c9cf6ba8c8d47.webp 400w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead50_hu31b9b0587f2695c03240d66e69d5aef4_27727_1ab5b4c3a7081951e3e912026d63ccb7.webp 760w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead50_hu31b9b0587f2695c03240d66e69d5aef4_27727_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead50_hu31b9b0587f2695c03240d66e69d5aef4_27727_9e1685bca80c36af472c9cf6ba8c8d47.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;759&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 3&lt;/strong&gt;: As figure 2 but for a normalized lead time of 0.5
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-figure-4-as-figure-2-but-for-a-normalized-lead-time-of-025&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;0.25 lead-time calibration plot&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead25_hu2c02e0b230d2949f0f23e4c5afed84ac_27605_6954c7242f4ae369301b6edeab448e6f.webp 400w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead25_hu2c02e0b230d2949f0f23e4c5afed84ac_27605_016c76393c339ca7faba61fd8344d5e8.webp 760w,
               /post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead25_hu2c02e0b230d2949f0f23e4c5afed84ac_27605_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://www.crucialab.net/post/how-good-are-agora-forecasts/calibration_lead25_hu2c02e0b230d2949f0f23e4c5afed84ac_27605_6954c7242f4ae369301b6edeab448e6f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;759&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      &lt;strong&gt;Figure 4&lt;/strong&gt;: As figure 2 but for a normalized lead time of 0.25
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“AGORA forecasts are consistent with being well calibrated.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These results show the AGORA forecasts are consistent with being well calibrated
so it is not unreasonable to take the probabilities that AGORA produces at face
value. Prescriptions of how to make rational decisions in the face of uncertainty
often assume that quantitative probabilities can be assigned to potential outcomes.
AGORA prediction markets can be used as a source of these probabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article originally appeared on Medium as &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/hvmd/how-good-are-agora-forecasts-8065bf372067&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;How good are AGORA forecasts?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
